I want to talk to you about a title that
uh you may not like too well once you
hear it it's a title that may actually
cause you to cringe but I'm going to
give you the title anyway and that title
is called tough
love tough love it's a term we don't
usually
like um
how many of you like receiving tough
love yeah we we get you know many of us
get pictures of our parents giving us
tough
love no no no tough love and you know
God God gives us tough
love um you know and I know it you know
kind of sounds drawing but you know what
I believe that we ought to be thankful
for God's tough love
amen so that's what we're going to talk
about today tough love and uh guess what
we are going to go back to the Book of
Ezekiel so um I believe God has
something very important for us to to to
hear today
um let's go to Ezekiel chapter 3 and
then we're going to we're going to have
a word of prayer and get into this so
Ezekiel chapter
3 when you're there please say Amen
let's pray Heavenly
Father uh please bless us
Lord open your word to
us we thank you for your tough
love in Jesus name we pray
amen Ezekiel chapter
3 beginning with verse one
the Bible says moreover he said unto me
son of man eat that thou findest eat
this roll and go speak unto the house of
Israel so I opened my mouth and he
caused me to eat the roll and he said
unto me son of
man cause thy belly to eat and fill thy
bowels with this roll that I give thee
then did I eat and it was in my mouth as
honey for
sweetness and he said unto me son of man
go get thee unto the house of Israel and
speak with my words unto them for thou
art not sent to a people of a strange
speech and of and hard language but to
the house of Israel not to many people
of a strange uh of a strange speech and
of a hard language whose words thou
cannot understand surely had I sent thee
to them they would have hearkened unto
thee but the house of Israel will not
hearken unto thee for they will not
hearken unto me for all the house of
Israel are an impotent and are impotent
and Hard
Hearted verse eight behold I have made
thy face strong against their faces and
thy forehead strong against their
foreheads as an adamant harder than
Flint have I made thy forehead fear them
not neither be dismayed at their looks
though they be a rebellious
house God is calling Ezekiel into his
prophetic Ministry and one of the first
things he says to Ezekiel is I'm sending
you to a hardheaded people and I am
going to make you hard-headed
Ezekiel I don't want you to be afraid of
him do not fear their faces first thing
God tells Ezekiel is do not be afraid of
him how many of you believe that God
wants to say the same thing to you that
he is saying the same thing to you he's
saying listen they're hard but I'm going
to make you hard as well they're tough
but I'm going to make you tough as well
he said I want you Ezekiel to not have
any fear in your
heart for them don't be
scared don't be afraid
well why why is God telling Ezekiel this
who is Ezekiel going up against he's
going up against a rebellious house a
rebellious people a people that will not
hear God in fact if you come down with
me to verse
25 you will see here in chapter 3: 25 it
says but thou son of man behold they
shall put bands upon thee and shall B
thee with them and thou shalt not go out
among them in other words God is kind of
warning Ezekiel Ezekiel listen here's
why I don't want you to be afraid of
them because they're going to come after
you they're going to try to make life
miserable for you they're going to be
your worst enemies they're going to bind
you they are going to do everything they
possibly can to shut you up but I do not
want you to be afraid of
them now let me ask you a question how
many of you if I told you that your your
neighbors your your family your friends
your your co-workers or just people that
you don't even know are going to attempt
to destroy who you are how many of you
would be a little bit nervous about that
a little bit how many of you would be a
lot nervous about that all right very
good you know we don't want we don't
like people coming at us like that but
God says to Ezekiel here do not fear
them I mean it sounds like God is being
tough what do you think
and he wants Ezekiel to be tough do not
be afraid of them that's his message to
Ezekiel in
fact if you hold your place here and
just come over with me to Ezekiel
chapter 8 let me show you a little bit
more about these people who God is
saying do not fear in Ezekiel chapter 8
beginning with verse 6 the Bible says
here God speaking to Ezekiel he said
furthermore unto me son of man see thou
what they do and even greater
Abominations that the house of Israel
committed here that I should go far off
from My Sanctuary but turn thee yet
again and thou shalt see greater
Abominations and he brought me to the
door of the court and when I looked
Behold a hole in the wall then he said
unto me son of man dig now in the wall
and when I died in the wall Behold a
door and he said unto me go in and
Behold The Wicked Abominations that they
do there and and Ezekiel 8 is really God
showing Ezekiel all these Abominations
that the children of Israel were doing
so God is trying to give Ezekiel this
picture of the people he's telling them
do not fear them do
not be
afraid come back with me to Ezekiel
chapter 3 Ezekiel chapter 3 after God
gives Ezekiel this this this appeal
after he say says to them do not be
afraid do not fear he then says Ezekiel
this is your mission this is what I want
you to do in verse
17 son of
man I have made thee a Watchman unto the
house of Israel therefore hear the word
at my mouth and give them warning from
me when I say unto the wicked Thou shalt
surely die and thou givest him not
warning nor speaketh to warn the wicked
from his Wicked way to save his life the
same Wicked man shall die in his
iniquity but his blood will I require at
thine hand all right so do you get what
what God just said to Ezekiel here he's
saying when I commission you to go speak
to go warn the wicked and you don't warn
them they will die for their sins but I
will hold you accountable let me ask a
question how many of you if I to ask do
that sound like tough love how many of
you would raise your hand say that
sounds like tough love yeah let me see
your hands that sounds like tough love
okay okay let's let's read on uh uh
verse Verse 18 or verse verse 19 yet if
thou warn the wicked if he turn not from
his Wicked wickedness nor from his
Wicked way he shall die in his iniquity
but thou has delivered thy Soul again
when a righteous man does turn from his
righteousness and committeth iniquity
and I lay a stumbling block before him
he shall die because thou has not given
him warning he shall die in his sin and
his right righteousness which he has
done shall not be remembered but his
blood will I require at thine hand
nevertheless if thou warn the righteous
man that the righteous sin not and he
does not sin he shall surely live
because he is warned also thou Hast
delivered thy soul in other words he's
saying to Ezekiel I'm sending you to go
speak don't be afraid of them and if you
don't
speak I will hold you
accountable for their loss
sound
tough
yeah many of you don't look happy right
now because you know what does God call
us to go speak does he call us not to be
afraid does he call us to have tough
love absolutely
absolutely
so after he explains ezekiel's Mission
the question then is how is God going to
do this how is God going to make it so
that Ezekiel does not fear them how is
God going to make ezekiel's heart and
mind as adamant as Flint that's what the
Bible says I'm going to make you as
adamant you know what adamant mean it
means you know you when someone's when
someone is adamant about
something stubborn I'm going to make you
stubborn like I'm going to make you more
stubborn than them yeah they may be
hard-headed I'm going to make you more
hard-headed than them
how is God going to do this in
Ezekiel how is he going to make it so
that Ezekiel becomes this person come
back with me to Ezekiel chapter 1 you'll
remember that we we went into this
chapter in detail last week but I need
you to see this okay I need you to
follow this Ezekiel chapter
1 this is where God or Ezekiel
encounters God you remember that yes and
and I want you to watch what happens in
this Vision because Ezekiel caught this
vision and the Bible says in verse four
and I looked and behold a whirlwind came
out of the North a great cloud and a
what a fire infolding
itself and a brightness was about it and
out of the midst thereof as the color of
amber and out of the midst of the fire
so pause right here when when Ezekiel
looks at this Vision he he sees this
Whirlwind coming and it looks the
Whirlwind looks like it's coming it's
surrounded with what with fire okay all
right that's Ezekiel 1:4 jump down with
me to or let's continue reading verse 5
and out of the midst thereof came the
likeness of four living creatures and
this was their appearance they had the
likeness of a man so the four living
creatures that Ezekiel Saw that we will
not go into detail today but these four
living creatures were in the midst of
the what of the fire so the whole time
what is Ezekiel looking at the fire he's
looking at the fire let's keep reading
verse
13 as for the likeness of the living
creatures their appearance was like
burnt coals of what fire and the
likeness and like the appearance of
lamps it went up and down the living
creatures and the fire was bright and
out of the fire went forth lightning so
the living creatures themselves look
like what they look like fire they're
covered in
fire so the Whirlwind is what fire the
living creatures are in the midst of the
Whirlwind which is fire and the living
creatures themselves are what fire then
then then notice with me Ezekiel 1: 27
now he sees this man sitting on a throne
above the entire vision and we know that
man is none other than Jesus Christ and
the Bible says in verse 27 and I saw
verse 26 and above the firmament that
was over their heads was the likeness of
a Throne as the appearance of a sapphire
throne and the likeness of the throne
was like the likeness of the appearance
of and I'm sorry and upon the likeness
of the throne uh was the likeness as the
appearance of a man above it now pause
for a second if you're familiar with the
Book of Daniel Daniel caught a vision of
this same throne and the Bible says in
the Book of Daniel his throne was like a
fiery flame and his wheels as burning
what fire do you remember in this Vision
that's in in the Book of Daniel but in
this Vision does Ezekiel see wheels does
he see a throne so we know that those
Throne that throne and those wheels are
surrounded by what fire listen watch
this watch this verse 27 and I saw as
the color of amber as the appearance of
Fire roundout Within it and the
appearance of his loins that is this man
even upward and from the appearance of
his loins even downward I saw as it were
the appearance of fire and it had
brightness round about it as the
appearance of a bow that is in the cloud
in the day of the rain so that the
appearance of the of the brightness
round about this was the appearance of
the lightness of the glory of the Lord
and when I saw it I fell upon my
face Ezekiel is
watching fire
Ezekiel is
beholding
fire
fire okay
no Ezekiel is
watching
fire do do do you see what I'm doing
when when I'm using the term fire I I'm
I'm kind of giving an emphasis of fire
because you know a fire is symbolic of
something in the
Bible I I want you to check this out
Ezekiel if let's say that you were
standing next to Ezekiel right and you
could not see what he was looking at but
if you were to look into Ezekiel eyes do
you think you would
see the
reflection of Fire so so would it be
safe for us to say that Ezekiel was
getting fire in his
eyes yeah yeah you know the Bible says
that by beholding we become we become
check this out guys God says to Ezekiel
Ezekiel I have made
you are you with me I have made you ezel
I'm going to put a passion in you that
outdoes them
I'm going to I'm going to put a fire in
you that outdoes
theirs and how does Ezekiel get this
fire he gets this fire by beholding
amen the vision of
God in the very next chapter Ezekiel
chapter 2 I want you to watch this
Ezekiel chapter 2 verse 2 the Bible says
in Ezekiel 2:2 verse one he said unto me
son of man stand up upon thy feet and I
will speak unto thee and the spirit
entered into me when he spake unto me
all right so what entered into him the
what was that Spirit the Holy Spirit
where was the Holy Spirit in in chapter
one it was it was in what it was in fire
so God Ezekiel is beholding this fire
and then God puts that fire into Ezekiel
yes
amen and now he says Ezekiel now now I'm
sending you he could not send Ezekiel
had he not seen the
fire now Ezekiel gets this fire and now
we got to understand something here
because what Ezekiel is seeing here this
Vision how would you describe the vision
like give me some some words that you
would use to describe what you're seeing
single words if you add just just help
me out like how would you describe it if
you were Ezekiel awesome what else
powerful powerful what else hly holy
what
else say again what over
overpowering what
cleansing
overwhelming amazing
amazing awesome all right so so these
are the words like whoa this is like why
is God showing me this and there's a
reason why you see God wanted Ezekiel to
focus on the fire listen carefully turn
with me to the Song of Solomon let's get
it up on this screen Song of Solomon
chapter 8 we want to read verses 6-8
check this out
guys Song of Solomon chapter 8 set
me set me as a seal upon thine heart as
a seal upon thine arm for love is as
strong as what death jealousy as cruel
as a grave the cause thereof pause for a
second the cuse of what the cause of
what no the cuse thereof so what's the
thereof referring back
to jealousy and
what two things love all right so check
out the Cs of jealousy and
love of are coals of what fire which has
a most vem flame look at the next verse
verse
7even many water
cannot
quench love pause for a
second in the Bible fire is the symbol H
for what
holy in the Bible fire is symbolic of
love when Ezekiel is beholding this fire
what is he
beholding he is
beholding God's
awesome
overwhelming what other words did we
use
Amazing Power he was
beholding
love okay it's
tough hold on hold on I I hold your
thought I need you to follow
this you
see is
it the problem of human nature to
misunderstand the character of
God when Ezekiel is beholding this
awesome
powerful this amazing looking thing
happening before his eyes what he is
beholding is the love of
God God takes this love and puts it in
Ezekiel and then says
Ezekiel
I am making you
adamant in love
okay
Ezekiel I am giving you
tough
love you're going to needed Ezekiel why
because you're gr up against a
rebellious and stubborn
people you're gr up with people who who
will Who will attempt to rob you of love
so Ezekiel I'm going to give
you
tough
love see when we hear that word tough
love we just get these bad pictures of
tough love that means god is about to do
something mean and call it
love that's how the world spins tough
love but beloved God's tough love is
different from the world's tough
love God's tough love is not I'm going
to punish you and you're going to like
it anyway cuz it's good for you God's
tough love is I love you despite
yourself I love you despite your
rebellious attitude I love you despite
your your continual denial of me my love
is
greater than your
Rebellion I love you with a tough
love are you catching that I I want that
that title tough love I know when you
first heard it oh tough love you I don't
want tough love from God can he just
love me God loves
you it and it's tough
love it's a love that is strong it is a
love that is passionate it is a love
that is fierce this same word uh um uh
love is stronger than death back in
verse six where it says love is stronger
than death that same word stronger or
strong as death is translated fierce in
other places in other words God's love
is
fierce he loves you
fiercely that's what it means when I
tell you God has
tough love for you and we ought to be
thankful cuz of God love was not tough
we'd all be lost cuz we are hard people
to deal
with are you with me God's love is tough
because he loves us with an everlasting
love so so so when he puts this in
Ezekiel you got to check this out how
many of you know some of the things
Ezekiel was asked to
do he was asked to cook a meal over
feces
yet that's in the
Bible and he was asked to do this to
demonstrate the vess that the children
of Israel had put themselves
in Ezekiel was asked to lay on one side
for 40 days one
side Ezekiel was asked to to go out
before the Israelites and put up this
tile and then Siege the tile and and do
all kinds of things that would have
looked crazy to the normal person and
God says to Ezekiel Ezekiel I need you
to have the kind of love that will make
you look foolish in front of your
enemies did you did you catch that
Ezekiel would not have done these things
had he not received the tough love of
God you see beloved God requires us to
have tough
love what is tough love
it's when you love
those who sometimes are not
lovable that's what tough love is not
what you give to someone yeah you know I
had to rebuke you brother tough luck
that's not tough
love do you get what I'm saying I mean
yes we when we rebuke someone It Isn't
Love but we have this idea of tough love
being that which we give to others for
their own own good beloved real tough
love is when you love that which is not
lovable which is all of
us right because we all have sinned and
fallen short of the glory of
God tough
love is having your love being stronger
than the worst thing someone else can do
to
you that's tough
love you see
Ezekiel would not have been motivated to
go and
speak had he not received the tough love
of
God in fact the reason why God said to
Ezekiel Ezekiel if you don't warn them
I'm holding you accountable is this it's
not that God was just being arbitrary it
was God saying to Ezekiel listen my love
ought to drive you to warn the wicked of
their ways and if you are indifferent
toward the wicked it lets me know that
my love is not in you you don't have
love in you you have hate in you and if
you have hate in you you are rebelling
against me did did you catch that it's
not God saying you better go tell him
and if you don't I'mma get you that's
not what God is saying God is saying if
you can watch the wicked
perish something's wrong with
you the love of God is Not In
You beloved God loves us with a tough
love and he expects us to have tough
love you see for many of us we our love
is not strong
enough to go do what God has asked us to
do to go speak to our you know we are
afraid of what the person might say if
we share are you catching me we are
afraid of their faces and God says I
want you to love them more than you fear
them I want you to love them greater
than the hard looks on their faces I
need you to have tough love come on man
toughen
up I need you to have tough
love you see Ezekiel he was called the
son of man over 96 times in the Bible do
you know that there's only one other
person in the Bible called son of man 96
times to be ex act and that is Jesus
Christ so God sending Ezekiel as the son
of man saying I want you to be my
representative to a rebellious people
and I want you to demonstrate to them my
tough love I want you to demonstrate to
them what you saw in Ezekiel
1 I want you to take that Vision I'm
going to put it inside you and I want
you to demonstrate that kind of love
towards them so beloved when Jesus
Christ came he did the same thing as the
son of man his purpose was to
demonstrate the love of God to us the
tough love of God come come with me
Isaiah chapter 50 I want you to notice
this Isaiah chap 50: 4 to8 Isaiah
chapter
50: 4 to8 listen to what the Bible says
here Isaiah 50:4 the Lord God has given
me the tongue of the learned that I
should know how to speak a word in
season to him that is weary he wakeneth
morning by morning he wakeneth mine ear
to hear as the learn this is this is a a
a Messianic verse we're reading this is
regarding Jesus verse 5 the Lord God has
opened my ear and I was not rebellious
neither turned away my back I gave my
back to the smiters and my cheeks to
them that plucked off the hair I hid not
my face from shame and spitting for the
Lord God will help me there therefore
shall I not be confounded therefore have
I set my face like
a okay
pause
pause what did Ezekiel what did God say
to
Ezekiel I'm going to make your I'm going
to make you like Flint check this out
guys when Jesus was coming to this earth
he said I'm setting my face like a
flint what does that
mean you think you're heart
you think you're hard let me show you
let me show you what toughness
is and Jesus comes to this Earth as a
man and Satan uses
humanity and say all right we're going
to see who's
tougher I'm going to make them hate you
with everything I have and Jesus was
like all
right and I'm going to show you how
tough are you catching this I'm going to
show you how tough my love
is and so think about this with me guys
on the
cross the world is throwing everything
it has against Jesus yeah if you're the
Son of God come down they are spitting
up him they're they're mocking him
they're doing everything possible to the
point where Jesus even believes that God
has forsaken
him their hatred was
tough but Jesus's
love was
tougher Jesus beloved had tough
love and he demonstrated that on the
cross in other words beloved listen to
me you and I cannot see what Ezekiel
Saw we weren't there for that but we can
catch the same vision in Christ lifted
up on the
cross that same fire that same Glory
that same power that same awesomeness
that same every word we just use all of
that is summed up in the vision of
Christ on the
cross because when we see Christ on the
cross what we see is
fire what we see
is
love what we see is
tough
love he loved us with an
everlasting
love his love was greater than the worst
thing they could throw at him which was
death therefore love was stronger than
death that beloved is tough
love tough love is not something that
makes other people angry at
you tough love is loving angry
people tough
love is loving the
unlovely tough love is when you keep
getting rejected and and rejected over
and over again I don't want your God I
don't want you tough love is
persistently going after the
lost and beloved you are you will not be
willing to yield to that kind of that
kind of humility if you have not first
caught the
vision of the
Cross you see when Ezekiel Saw Christ
high and lifted up the Bible says he
fell
down he
he was
humbled so when God now said okay
Ezekiel this is what I want you to do I
want you to go and do this I know it's
going to look crazy in front of the
people but I need you to go do this for
me Ezekiel was like Hey not a
problem
humility hum ezekiel's vision of Christ
made him
humble and he was willing to be used
however God chose him to be used
tough
love and Ordinary Love cannot lead you
to do the things that Ezekiel
did I want you to IM see for us you know
go knock on that door what oh and we
pass out right I mean think about it
compare that to
Ezekiel compare it to the things E True
Love tough love will lead us to no
longer fear their
faces that's what tough love
does you know when Jesus came forth from
the grave you can imagine the fear of
his enemies can you imagine that like
let's say you kill somebody right you
you conspir to kill somebody and you and
your friend made the whole plan and
we're going to take him out to the
backyard and we're going to shoot him
we're going to bury his
body and then you do that and in like 4
days later he comes back to
life with Supernatural Powers all right
man how many of you are locking yourself
in a room forever and ever more right
how many of you can't go to sleep at
night because you think he might appear
by your bedside and be like all right
it's Revenge time I want you to imagine
the fear that the Jews had of Jesus when
they heard he was alive
are you with me I mean their natural
minds are thinking well if that was me
I'm coming for
revenge and in fact the disciples when
they see Jesus alive they're like whoa
okay
so is it time to take care of business
Lord are you going to restore the
kingdom meaning are you going to punish
those that did this to
you Jus says
come here's what I want you to do all
right here's the plan what Jesus
I want you to go yeah yeah it's going to
be good go yeah yeah
and I'm
first preach the
gospel what yeah I want you to go to the
house of
Israel and I want you to share with them
that my love is stronger than death
I want you to share with them that my
love is
tough I have tough love for
them Lord the people that put you to
yeah the people that put me to death I
want you to go find them and I want you
to tell
them that I have tough
love see Beloved the Bible says greater
love has no man than this than a man lay
his life down for his
friends that's tough
love the world needs tough love from
us do you catch that the world need and
too often we give the world the wrong
kind of tough
love yeah we give them judgment we give
them all kinds of things that are not
the tough love that God is trying to
have us demonstrate to
them see that tough love is easy it's
easy for us to you know I don't care
what it's
hard to really really love when you're
not being loved
back that is tough love that is adamant
love your love for the world must be
stronger than their hate for you
did you catch that your love for the
world must be stronger than their Jesus
says if your enemy feed him if your
enemy hunger feed them Paul said that if
your enemy hunger feed them for in so
doing you will Heap hot
coals of fire you know what those coals
of fire are you're heaping
love you need to be throwing love stones
at people what take this and that's how
much I love you right
Heap hot coals of fire upon their heads
that's not a bad thing that's a good
thing you're heaping love upon your
enemies
so you'll remember that in the Book of
Ezekiel he sees the glory of God and
then he's given a
scroll and then he's told to go
preach
wow he's given this from
a being who has a rainbow round about
him and shines like the sun wow
wow because beloved in Revelation chap
10 there's another Vision that
corresponds right to that and it's the
vision of this Angel this apparent Angel
who has a rainbow round about him and
his face is shining as the sun and he
has a scroll in his hand and in
Revelation chap 10 we understand that
God is giving that scroll to the Advent
people amen
and beloved what we need to understand
that is that as the Advent people when
he says eat the scroll and you must go
and prophesy before many peoples Nations
kindreds and tongues that we will not
go if we have not first caught the
fire if we have not first caught the
vision of Christ lifted up on the cross
and what that tough love means for us
because when we see that vision for what
it truly is we too will fall at our feet
at his feet we too will stand up with
fire in our
eyes and we too will go as God has
commanded
us not because we're
afraid but
because we now have tough
love tough love
that's what it's all about
guys tough love I want to make an appeal
as I invite Randy to come forward and
pray your love isn't
tough you get offended
easily you're mad
what your love is very weak it's puny
and today you're realizing in a way that
you never have before Lord I need tough
love and I don't have it I need it none
of us before this have asked for tough
love we hate tough love I don't want no
now we understand I want tough
love and today you're saying yes Lord
please I need to catch a vision of
Christ on the cross because I need
tougher
love if that's you in here and this it
may not be all of you this is a this is
a individual appeal today okay if that's
you today and you're saying Lord I need
that tough love I'm going to ask you if
you would stand where you
are again this is not for everyone and
you know what if you have that love
praise God it is not impossible to have
that love so if you have that love
praise God you you you remain seated
praise God no one's looking at you funny
but if you're saying today Lord I need
that love I need that
love give me tough love
because my love needs to be greater than
what the world or anyone can do to
me you're standing to your
feet because you want that love in your
heart and for those of you who who who
have not stood yet and you want to be a
part of this appeal I invite you to
stand Lord just help me to continue to
love my my children my husband my spouse
uh my my what my neighbors help me to to
love them with the love that you have
loved me with you love me with tough
love help me to love others with that
same tough love if you want to stand as
well please stand with us Randy is going
to lead us as we
pray by your
love we want to be your vessels to share
it with the
world we realize our weakness Lord our
failures but we
choose to behold your strength your
power your
goodness we know without you we can do
nothing so
please father give us the mind of Christ
give us a love for
others work in us help us to continue to
behold Jesus lifted up on the
cross and then send us out Lord with
boldness and faith and we thank you in
jesus' name amen amen